# GRIGORIY OVCHINNIKOV

Georgia, Tbilisi

✓ ogoje@protonmail.com 🛅 grigoriy-o-a679501b5/ 🕥 JointEntropy

Data Scientist with 4 years of data analysis and machine learning experience. Strong knowledge of classical, advanced ML algorithms and statistics. Proficiency in working with ML frameworks and databases for business problem-solving.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, Bash

Machine learning: Scikit-learn, XGBoost, LightGBM, CatBoost, PyTorch, SciPy, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib,

Plotly, Seaborn, pulearn, shap, MLflow

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Cassandra, HBase

Deployment: Git

Google Cloud Platform: Cloud Functions, Cloud Run, Kubernetes Engine

Big data: Hadoop, Hive, Pyspark

Natural Language Processing: gensim, nltk, transformers

Web scraping: Scrapy, Puppeteer, lxml

Infrastructure: Docker

Project management: Jira, Confluence, Trello

Other: EDA, Data cleaning, Visualization, Modeling, Propensity Modelling, Model interpretation, Deployment,

Natural Language Processing, Fuzzy matching, Statistics, Experimental design, Hypothesis testing, MVP

## **EXPERIENCE**

Platforma November 2020 – Present

Middle Data Scientist

Moscow, Russia

- Department of data analysis and modeling.
- Look-alike modelling, positive unlabeled (PU) learning.
- User profiling using clickstream data analysis.
- Building user interests vectors.
- Host representation learning(item2vec).
- Pipeline stack: Python, Hadoop, Pyspark, Airflow, PyTorch.

### S7 TechLab

October 2018 - October 2020

Moscow, Russia

Junior Data Scientist

- Big data department.
- Predictive maintenance task, remaining useful life estimation.
- Development of decision support system with cluster analysis and supervised multiclass classification.
- Scraping external data with Python.
- Building MVP with R Shiny, Python Flask-restx.
- Pipeline stack: Python, Airflow, PySpark, S3, PostgreSQL, Cassandra, Kafka.

### **EDUCATION**

National Research Nuclear University (MEPhI)

Master's degree in Applied Mathematics and Informatics(incomplete)

September 2018 – June 2020

September 2014 – June 2018

Moscow, Russia

Volgograd State Technical University(VSTU)

Bachelor's degree in Informatics and Computer Engineering

Volgograd, Russia